<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Jeffrey H.</title>
  
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/"/>
  <updated>2021-01-16T16:53:19.621Z</updated>
  <id>https://thejeffrey.me/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Jeffrey H.</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Execution is everything</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2021/01/16/execution-is-everything/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2021/01/16/execution-is-everything/</id>
    <published>2021-01-16T15:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-16T16:53:19.621Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Knowledge is not power, it is potential power. Execution will trump knowledge any day - Tony Robbins</p></blockquote><p>A lot of people saying that knowledge is power, without knowledge we can’t do anything, but owning knowledge without action also do nothing. I have been too influenced by Knowledge, I enjoy learning new things but yet less execution. The necessity of taking action appropriately is more powerful than knowing knowledge.</p><p>How many people around you know a lot of things but do nothing about it? We regularly find out the issue but do not take any action to fix it. We used to ignore the issue since it is easier than find out the solution. As is told that knowledge without action is useless. We all know that we must take action but it is easier said than done.</p><p>I’m not saying that learning knowledge is useless. Action without knowledge is aimless, it may bring in more troubles, we can’t go somewhere we are not familiar with without a navigator. Nowadays we can learn everything from internal everywhere every time. Everyone can get knowledge, it is cheap without execution. Gaining knowledge and understanding is wisdom, it is the first step before taking action, it was a tool waiting to be used. However, missing out on the action leaves our knowledge worthless. </p><p>Learning how to swim from a swimming video doesn’t make us really can swim, it needs real practice and implementation. As reading provides knowledge, it also ensures that the necessary action needs to be taken. </p><p>Knowledge is like an ax, it needs someone to use it to cut down a tree. This making the idea a simple yet powerful weapon. </p><blockquote><p>You do not get paid for having ideas. You get paid for making them happen. - Richard Branson</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is not power, it is potential power. Execution will trump knowledge any day - Tony Robbins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ikigai - a reason for being</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2021/01/11/ikigai-a-reason-for-being/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2021/01/11/ikigai-a-reason-for-being/</id>
    <published>2021-01-11T14:55:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T15:47:45.062Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In Japan, Ikigai is a concept of having a meaningful direction in life. It is a philosophy about finding a reason for being. It is about doing something you love and you are good at it, with the possibility of bringing value to other people. In most cases, Ikigai does not refer only to one’s purpose in life, without regard to others or society. It is captured by the Ikigai diagram and includes overlapping these spheres, Love, Good At, Paid For, and Needs.</p><p>This diagram helps us gain further insights into our purpose in life and seeking what we are enjoying to do.</p><p><img src="/images/ikigai.png" alt="Luck Surface Area" title="Ikigai"></p><p>What you love:<br>The things that bring us the most joy in life and make us feel fulfilled. It can a hobby, exercise, reading, or spending leisure time with people. The things do not matter whether we are good at it or we can get paid for doing it.  </p><p>What you are good at:<br>The skills you learned, talented, and be expert in. It can be sports, painting, or public speaking. However, it can also a thing that you are good at but you don’t like.</p><p>What the world needs:<br>The world here might be a small community or a global trending demand that people want. The world’s needs might include IT, engineering, medical, or innovation. This sphere involved other people and beyond people’s needs.</p><p>What you can get paid for:<br>This is related to the things that people talented at but it getting lower paid. It might be singing or passionate about art. Whether it can get higher paid depended on the demand.</p><p>There is further meaning that overlapping spheres in the diagram.</p><blockquote><blockquote><blockquote></blockquote><p>Good At + Love = Passion<br>Love + Needs = Mission<br>Needs + Paid For = Vocation<br>Paid For + Good At = Profession</p><blockquote></blockquote></blockquote></blockquote><p>The best spot within this Ikigai diagram would involve every point together. I am passionate about programming, am also skilled at it, there is a need for it in my world at the time, and I have an enjoyable job in this field with well paid. I would say I have found my Ikigai for my life.</p><p>When you love your job, it is not a job anymore.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;In Japan, Ikigai is a concept of having a meaningful direction in life. It is a philosophy about finding a reason for being. It is about 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Being wrong is not wronged</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2021/01/02/being-wrong-is-not-wronged/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2021/01/02/being-wrong-is-not-wronged/</id>
    <published>2021-01-02T15:55:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-02T18:08:10.957Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>You should take the approach that you’re wrong. Your goal is to be less wrong. - Elon Musk</p></blockquote><p>As Elon Musk said, being wrong or failed is always an option because if you are not, means you are not improving.</p><p>We all make mistakes, and we do it regularly without noticing it. No one enjoys being wrong, it is a negative emotional experience for all of us. The important thing is how do we respond when it happened to us. Some people will take responsibility and address it quickly. Some people will feel embarrassing to admit their mistake. Some people stubbornly denying being wrong and escape from the failure. People’s egos and emotions will make thing goes worth even they know it is wrong, it is hard to control the emotions.</p><p>Don’t try to shift the blame to other people. Other people might make mistakes or do wrong things with us, but we should focus only on our part. We should not argue that the mistake is caused by others. Even if they don’t admit it, but we know that we did the right thing by admitting our wrongs.</p><p>We all know admitting we are wrong is a virtue and having this habit will benefit us in our life. Struggling to admit our fault can harm our interpersonal relationship. Admitting we are wrong doesn’t mean that we are a loser. In fact, being able to own up to our mistakes takes a lot of courage and self-awareness. It is a sign of improvement. People won’t consider us a bad guy instead, they would probably respect our guts and sincerity.</p><p>After admitting and owning the mistake, we should do reflection, walking through the mistake, and learn from it provided we don’t repeat the same mistakes. The ability to fail, learn something new, and then find a solution until it works.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should take the approach that you’re wrong. Your goal is to be less wrong. - Elon Musk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Elon Musk
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hard Skills vs. Soft Skills</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/12/27/hard-skills-vs-soft-skills/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/12/27/hard-skills-vs-soft-skills/</id>
    <published>2020-12-27T15:59:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-27T17:24:24.982Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Hard skills are skills where the rules stay the same regardless of which company, circumstance, or people you work with. In contrast, soft skills are skills where the rules changes depending on the company culture and people you work with. - Lei Han</p></blockquote><p>Hard skills are measurable and most often technical skills, such as accounting and engineering. Soft skills are intangible and difficult to quantify, such as leadership and communication.</p><p>In work, hard skills help us to make confident decisions, but they do not help the foundation of communication and interaction with people around us. Business is not a machine, it is groups of people working together to achieve something.</p><p>LinkedIn CEO Jeff Weiner says “interpersonal skills are where we’re seeing the biggest imbalance. Communications is the number one skills gap”. LinkedIn’s 2018 Workforce Report found that the four most in-demand soft skills are leadership, communication, collaboration, and time management. </p><p>Soft skills can be very hard to learn since it required an internal mind change. There is some debate about the importance of soft skills and hard skills that affect work or life. However, they are both necessary and equivalent to one another.</p><p>Soft skills often provide the foundation for high emotional intelligence (EQ). EQ is the ability to identify and manage our emotions, and also the ability to understand one’s emotions. When Intelligence Quotient (IQ) is related to technical skills, EQ accounts for 90% of what makes people move up the success ladder.</p><p>Mind-body awareness is an important soft skill. It helps us from reading the room and reading others before we are consciously aware of them. Mind-body practices such as yoga and meditation help us monitor ourselves and understand our mind. This kind of self-awareness also increases empathy. Empathy is useful in work or life. Think the way of others, put ourselves in one’s shoes, help us understand more in the circumstance, and control our emotions. Such habits allow us to engage more deeply with other people.</p><p>Focus on improving soft skills such as listening and empathy with a growth mindset that will bring us an unfair advantage in work and life.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hard skills are skills where the rules stay the same regardless of which company, circumstance, or people you work with. In 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>High-income skills</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/12/19/high-income-skills/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/12/19/high-income-skills/</id>
    <published>2020-12-19T15:55:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-19T17:23:15.177Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A high-income skill is a skill that you be able to leverage to get more paid. It’s often a soft skill than a hard skill. Like communication, passion, or reliability. It delivers a unique value to your organization and allows you to control your salary because you will be in high demand.</p><blockquote><p>Your income right now is a result of your standards, it is not the industry, it is not the economy. - Tony Robbins</p></blockquote><p>You don’t always achieve your goals but you always improve your standard by doing it. To develop high-income skills, you need to increase your confidence with body language and communicate in the same ways as high earners. From the organization to the family, unclear communication can mess up everything. High-income earners consistently rate clear communication as an unfair advantage.</p><p>People who earn a high income drives every decision with their passion. When we living our life with passion, we living life instead of working a job.  We can find meaning in our work instead of just looking for the salary. A job can be a larger life strategy. High earners plan on how to leverage the existing resources they currently have to generate more income, this is the most powerful high-income skill.</p><p>Believe in the impossible is simply telling ourselves we can do it. At the end of the day, we won’t try the impossible if we don’t think there is a chance of success. In every moment, imagine that you are a high earner, what will you do in the current situation, learn a new skill to solve the problem if necessary. </p><p>As Tony Robbins said, “Who you spend time with is who you become.” Surround ourselves with the right people is the most important thing. A negative environment can’t make us think positive. Successful people know the power of networking, they surround themselves with people they wanted to become. Find people who achieved what we want, figure out how they did it, and modeling them. </p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;A high-income skill is a skill that you be able to leverage to get more paid. It’s often a soft skill than a hard skill. Like communicati
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Surround yourself with people you aspire to be</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/12/12/surround-yourself-with-people-you-aspire-to-be/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/12/12/surround-yourself-with-people-you-aspire-to-be/</id>
    <published>2020-12-12T15:55:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-12T17:29:58.149Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nowadays we are no longer demographics, we are psychographic. People living in the same area may have different interests or lifestyle. In the words of motivational speaker, Vusi Thembekwayo: “A kid living in Kuala Lumpur who has never been out of Kuala Lumpur sounds like a kid in Brooklyn New York because he watches Jay Z on Youtube. So he is completely immersed in that culture even though he never left his small little village.” No matter where we are, what we watch or read might change our identity. We will get influenced by those things we are interested in.</p><p>We often heard that “You are the average of the five people spend the most time with”. The people around you may shape who you are. When we are talking to a negative person, we will be affected by negative mindsets. When we are surrounded by people who love to talk about business, we will learn the knowledge of the business from them. People of a mind fall into the same group.</p><p>Successful people pay attention to networking. They care about who they spend time with and how people affected them. They proactively surround by people who more successful than themselves, so they can learn from them and keep improving. It is the key to have a growth mindset, which can be influenced by other people.</p><p>Surround with successful people may help you become successful. You might discover something from successful people in your subconscious mind without notice it. You might learn from their mindset, follow their way of thinking, and wanted to achieve success as them.</p><p>Hang out with people who inspire you to become better. Research for people you wanted to be an inspiration, learn from what they have done, and model them.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Nowadays we are no longer demographics, we are psychographic. People living in the same area may have different interests or lifestyle. I
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Law of Attraction</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/12/05/law-of-attraction/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/12/05/law-of-attraction/</id>
    <published>2020-12-05T15:45:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-05T17:33:50.274Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As an easy definition, the Law of Attraction is the belief that positive thoughts will bring positive experiences. It uses the power of our mind to translate whatever is in our thoughts and materialize them into reality. Simply put, all thoughts will turn into things eventually. If you think about negative things you will remain under that cloud. If you think about positive thoughts you will find a way to achieve them with action. We are acting as human magnets sending out our thoughts and emotions and attracting back more of what we have put out.</p><p>Many people think that the Law of Attraction is just visualizing what we want and wait for it to come. However, this is unreasonable. I think that is not exactly how it works. There is something missing in the idea, no matter how much time and effort we put into visualizing our success, all we will ever be is a person with a dream. As they said, we can’t have the things that we never had until we do the things that we have never done. We can’t do the same thing but expecting different results.</p><blockquote><p>Dreams don’t work unless you take action. - Roy T. Bennett</p></blockquote><p>In order to use the power of the Law of Attraction and make our dreams come true, there is one key ingredient we must integrate into our life: ACTION. Visualization and internal work are important but that doesn’t mean we can ignore the action step altogether. Once we have the inner work to get clear on mind, the action work comes far more easily. We have to take action and take all of the required steps to make our vision a reality. </p><p>As soon as we start to activate the Law of Attraction and gain more traction, it will be much easy to focus on positive things, ignore negative things, and achieve our goals.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;As an easy definition, the Law of Attraction is the belief that positive thoughts will bring positive experiences. It uses the power of o
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Distraction everywhere</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/11/30/distraction-everywhere/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/11/30/distraction-everywhere/</id>
    <published>2020-11-30T14:45:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-30T15:43:39.654Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Everything is different nowadays, distraction is everywhere and happened anytime. There are so many things that distracted our attention and took away our time. We take our smartphones with us everywhere we go, we spend a lot of time on social media, messages, and news. We got distracted more often than we’d like. The reason why we got it is one of the biggest secrets that most tech-companies don’t want us to know.</p><p>Dopamine Hacking. </p><blockquote><p>Dopamine is a neurochemical which is released every time your brain anticipates a reward such as entertainment, information, novelty, or stimulation.</p></blockquote><p>When dopamine is released, it makes us feel good, so our brain wants more of it. Just like a fat kid who loves chocolate cake. This is why our brain will stimulate us to repeat the behaviors that led to a dopamine release.</p><p>Common distractions such as social media, news, and even email have been intentionally designed to trigger an incredibly strong dopamine release. It is much more dopamine release than most of our work does. It is purposely chosen by the companies behind the apps. In fact, their entire business model depends on it. The stronger the dopamine release, the more time we will spend on these distractions, and the more money they make.</p><p>This is a concept called “attention-hacking”. It happened when we want to do something that matters most at the time like reading or study. We got distracted from our smartphone, it gave us an immediate response with dopamine release, we got addicted to it as we felt happy and enjoyable. It’s quickly destroying people’s ability to stay focused. Our brain is being hijacked by meaningless things, and it prevents us from working on meaningful things.</p><p>When we understand this concept, we will be able to easily block distractions in our daily life and allow us to focus deeply on things that truly matter.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Everything is different nowadays, distraction is everywhere and happened anytime. There are so many things that distracted our attention 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Success Leaves Clues</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/11/24/success-leaves-clues/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/11/24/success-leaves-clues/</id>
    <published>2020-11-24T15:45:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-24T17:12:59.849Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What is the key to success that they have picked up, but we can’t do it and even can’t see it. Success looks like a gift given to other people but not us. Why their success seems like effortless. </p><p>Success does not always based-on luck, it comes from hard work. If we are hungry enough, we put our effort to find a way to achieve success, with all in. We surround ourselves with the right people who managed to achieve something that we are looking for. It means surrounding the mindset of a winner and always tempting to achieve more. We can model their strategy.</p><p>Modeling means learning by following the behavior of other people. Humans naturally model each other, like children modeling their parents, follow what their parents do. Modeling is a technique used by those who willing to learn from other people. People who do modeling have a growth mindset. Those people believe that just as we learn behaviors, we can learn from the experiences of successful people. </p><p>Modeling also happens in the organization. The staff could be modeling his manager in doing some tasks, and often modeling is unintentional. Company culture is also a model that lead by the leaders in the organization, everyone modeling the culture involuntary.</p><p>Modeling in psychology has become a mainstream theory. Whether in career or life, select a person you admire to become, study the methodology behind their success, learn from their strategy, and follow the similar path to achieve it. Look for someone who already achieves the things that you wanted to do or someone who has created the kind of life that you want to live. Look into their history, what kind of difficulties they face, and how they overcome. Use their experiences to build a path to mirrors theirs.</p><blockquote><p>Success Leaves Clues - Tony Robbins</p></blockquote><p>Most successful people have the similar strategy that we can be modeling it. Modeling is a skill set that we can learn and keep improving on it.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;What is the key to success that they have picked up, but we can’t do it and even can’t see it. Success looks like a gift given to other p
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>First-principles</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/11/14/first-principles/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/11/14/first-principles/</id>
    <published>2020-11-14T14:45:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-15T08:18:20.604Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>First-principles thinking is one of the best ways of reverse engineering for complicated problems. The idea is to break down complicated problems into basic elements and then reassemble them from the group up.  First-principles is kind of a physics way of looking at the world. This way of thinking helps us removes the common assumptions that might be wrong, also knowns as Cognitive Bias.</p><p>Most of the time, people are reasoning by analogy. We look at something that was done before or something else that other people are doing it. A lot of things that we believe are based on some authority figure telling us that is true. As children, we learn to stop questioning when we are told “Because I said so.” As adults, we learn to stop questioning when people say “Because that’s how it works.”</p><blockquote><p>The important thing is not to stop questioning. Curiosity has its own reason for existence. - Albert Einstein</p></blockquote><p>Children instinctively think in first principles. They like to ask “Why” until they understand the thing. However, audits will always think that we are doing this because it is always been done that way. We are not doing it because nobody else ever done that, so it must not be good. But this is just a lazy way of thinking. We have to build up the reasoning from the group up. We can try to understand the reality with what is true, not with our intuition.  If we let other people think for us means that we are using their analogies or their experiences. People’s thinking is framed by someone else and it could be wrong.</p><p>The power of first-principles thinking is not only for improvement but also increases the possibility. Reasoning from first principles allows us to step outside of conventional wisdom. We can reason by first principles, by analogy, or a blend of the two.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;First-principles thinking is one of the best ways of reverse engineering for complicated problems. The idea is to break down complicated 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Same thing but different reaction</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/11/08/same-thing-but-different-reaction/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/11/08/same-thing-but-different-reaction/</id>
    <published>2020-11-08T15:15:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-08T15:54:41.098Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>It’s not what happens to you, but how you react to it that matters. - Epictetus</p></blockquote><p>What sets the world’s successful people apart is not what happens to them, but how they react to the things that happened to them. It’s their response to a challenge or a difficulty that separates them from most of us. When something happens, the only thing you can control is your attitude toward it, you can either accept it or blame it.</p><p>When we run into an obstacle such as the covid pandemic, it is easy to just give up and throw in the white towel. However, this will not be going to make our life any better. I saw a lot of people around me they think 2020 should end as quickly as possible to avoid any bad things happen. I don’t think that is a good mindset to have. I think that we can reflect on what we did during this crisis, and how we can improve on it. For example, we should prepare for uncertainty like having multiple sources of income for diversity. To be our best self as often as possible, be equipped for our path towards a better future.</p><p>If possible, inspire others to do the same in that process. Remember, we are in the same challenge together. People need a spark of light in these times, and we can decide to be that light. When we doing reflect on other people, we are learning from their experiences too, we can use it as our observation. </p><p>During the stay at home period, we can learn some new skills that will help us to be better, it is the time for us to improve ourself. Finish a few tasks that we are wanted to do for a long time, so we can start with a clean sheet.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not what happens to you, but how you react to it that matters. - Epictetus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What sets the world’s s
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-reflection" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-reflection/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>[Zero to One] Big lessons from dot-com bubble in Silicon Valley</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/11/02/zero-to-one-big-lessons-from-dot-com-bubble-in-silicon-valley/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/11/02/zero-to-one-big-lessons-from-dot-com-bubble-in-silicon-valley/</id>
    <published>2020-11-02T15:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-02T16:45:37.501Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Four big lessons that guide the business thinking from the entrepreneurs who come from Silicon Valley, after the dot-com bubble.</p><ol><li><p>Make incremental advances: A lot of entrepreneurs dream big and wanted to change the world. They are enjoying the brilliant idea that may change the way of how the world is working. They are seeking incredible fast growth and ignore the tiny little disadvantage. They prefer short term advantage instead of long term advantage. However, the focus on constant growth is the key. Small, incremental steps are the only safe path forward.</p></li><li><p>Stay lean and flexible: “All companies must be lean, which is code for unplanned.” We can’t predict the future of the business. We should not know what it will do, planning is inflexible. We should prepare for the unknown circumstances, assume that we will be affected by the uncertainty. Instead, we should try things out, and treat entrepreneurship as experimentation.</p></li><li><p>Improve on the competition: “Don’t try to create a new market prematurely.” We should start with an existing customer to know that we are in a real business. We should improve the existing products that are already offered by successful competitors. By doing this, we can recognize that we are building something that somebody wants. </p></li><li><p>Focus on product, not sales: “If your product requires advertising to sell it, it’s not good enough. The only sustainable growth is viral growth.” Salespeople are important, but the great product speaks for itself. Although we still need marketing, we should look at it as exposure. We should give the great product a chance to speaks.</p></li></ol><p>These lessons have become dogma in the startup world. We should focus more on real demand instead of bright future ideas. We need to rethink what is needed for people and what is good to have but not important.</p><blockquote><p>The most contrarian thing of all is not to oppose the crowd but to think for yourself. - Peter Thiel </p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Four big lessons that guide the business thinking from the entrepreneurs who come from Silicon Valley, after the dot-com bubble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Simple is as simple does</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/10/25/simple-is-as-simple-does/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/10/25/simple-is-as-simple-does/</id>
    <published>2020-10-25T15:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-10-25T16:46:24.044Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Occam’s Razor - William of Ockham</p></blockquote><p>Occam’s Razor is a mental model, problem-solving principle, to solve problems more quickly and efficiently. Explain in a nutshell, the simplest solution is often the best solution. When the thing can be simple, don’t make it complicated. When the complex solution and simple solution both work equally, we should choose the simple solution. The simpler a theory is, the more easily it can be verified. The simpler a solution is, the more easily it can be executed. </p><blockquote><p>Everything should be made as simple as possible, but not simpler. - Albert Einstein</p></blockquote><p>Sometimes, we want to implement a solution that can solve a lot of problems or issues. We want to put all the things that we have into one solution to prove that what we can do, but this will make things more complicated.  We try to create one method that can solve everything. However, this will make things complicated to understand, bring more mistakes to occur, and it is unlikely to lead to a manageable prediction.</p><p>A Mental model works best for making initial conclusions before the full information of the problem can be collected. We can have this mental model as a tool in our mental toolbox to give an immediate response when something happens.</p><p>Simple is as simple does, we can choose the easiest solution to get thing done. It is better than stuck in a complex solution and do nothing. You have got to see the forest before you can see the trees. </p><p>Nevertheless, if the complex solution does a better job than the simple solution, then we should pick the complex one. And making it too simple might not only be impracticable to solve the issue. Occam’s razor is not intended as a replacement for critical thinking. It is just a tool to help make that thinking more effective.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occam’s Razor - William of Ockham&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occam’s Razor is a mental model, problem-solving principle, to solve 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Waiting to be ready will be waiting forever</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/10/19/waiting-to-be-ready-will-be-waiting-forever/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/10/19/waiting-to-be-ready-will-be-waiting-forever/</id>
    <published>2020-10-19T15:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-10-25T16:45:43.261Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>“I don’t know what to do”<br>“I don’t know how to do it”<br>“I don’t have the chance to do it”<br>“I will be very hard working if I got the opportunity to do it”</p><p>When I look at people who hustle into something, work for his own business, I felt like if I got the chance to work on my own business, I will be very hard working too. However, how to get the chance is a big question for me. Most of the people have this feeling in their life too, we always waiting for someone to provide us the opportunity to spend time and hustle into something.</p><p>Refer to those articles that I read, and do some study on it, they always talk about some common points. If you want to master a skill, you have to understand it, it takes practice, time, and persistence. Ask yourself, who is the leader in the industry that is absolutely crushing it, who is the icon in that specific field, who is the first person that you recall in your mind. We can do some research on what makes them successful, what skills are required to achieve your target. Map out the list of things that you would like to implement and start practicing.</p><p>We should start with setting an intention, identify what skillset needs to learn, then comes practice, then comes failing, then comes learning, then it is a habit and becomes a part of you. Consistency is the key, consistency leads to habits. This learning process is a formula that we can implement in almost everything. </p><blockquote><p>It’s not what we do once in a while that shapes our lives. It’s what we do consistently. - Anthony Robbins</p></blockquote><p>Remind ourselves, if you wait to be ready, you will be waiting forever. Take the first step to get started is more important than waiting for the perfect time to start.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;“I don’t know what to do”&lt;br&gt;“I don’t know how to do it”&lt;br&gt;“I don’t have the chance to do it”&lt;br&gt;“I will be very hard working if I got t
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Three Mental Models to get started</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/10/11/three-mental-models-to-get-started/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/10/11/three-mental-models-to-get-started/</id>
    <published>2020-10-11T15:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-10-11T16:50:28.685Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mental Model represents how things work, or an explanation of a person’s thinking process. Our thinking quality is based on the models in the brain, and our brain will automatically trigger different thinking models in different situations. The more models you have, the bigger your toolbox will be, and you will be able to look at the same thing with different thinking models and different perspectives.</p><ol><li><p>Inversion<br>Its origins can be found in the word “invert”, which is simply means “turn upside down”. Normally, when we want to make a good impression, we will think about doing something good to prove ourselves, but we should think about what bad things we should not be done. It can also be like rather than thinking about what you want, consider what you’d like to avoid. </p></li><li><p>Second-order thinking<br>Every action has a consequence and further consequences, it like a chain, connecting every action or circumstance. These are called second-order effects. In this model of thinking, we can think about the chained effect that will happen with all the actions we take, to avoid potentially making a bad decision. Second-order thinking enables us to discover the long-term result of our actions.</p></li><li><p>Pareto Principle<br>Pareto Principle, also known as the 80/20 rule, often happens in our world, but we are not aware of it. The Pareto Principle specifies that for many results, 80% of consequences come from 20% of the causes. To put it simply, 80% of the result we got came from 20% of our hard work, which means that we should use 20% of our time to focus on the most important thing that can bring us 80% of a good result. Accept imperfection, and stop being a perfectionist.</p></li></ol><p>A mental model is a very good tool which can help us make better decisions in our life. However, it is not easily accessible but once we start using it, we will implement it on a daily basis in almost everything.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Mental Model represents how things work, or an explanation of a person’s thinking process. Our thinking quality is based on the models in
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Improve productivity inspired by Elon Musk</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/10/03/improve-productivity-inspired-by-elon-musk/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/10/03/improve-productivity-inspired-by-elon-musk/</id>
    <published>2020-10-03T15:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-10-03T16:30:34.576Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If let me think about the busiest person in the world, I immediately think of Elon Musk. How he can get so many things done every single day 24/7. He could be the Busyman in the business world, or whatever you name it. He managing Teala, SpaceX, The Boring Company, Neuralink, and the list keep going. Those companies he is working on that all changing the course of humanity. Even managing just one of those would be one hell of a project, every day dealing with uncertainty. I mean, with SpaceX alone he is trying to get us to Mars, this is insane.</p><p>Therefore, what does Elon Musk do differently from most other people, that makes him so extremely productive, get so many things done in all different area. Well, I think one thing is very clear, he is big on prioritization. He once said, “Focus on signal over noise. Don’t waste time on stuff that doesn’t actually make things better.” This sounds like a simple idea that everyone was known, but it is not easy to apply in our daily tasks. We always get disturbed by urgent things, even though that is not really urgent. </p><p>By considering reducing the things that don’t matter (much), he frees up his limited time and energy for the things that do matter, and that is something we should all learn from him and apply in our daily jobs. First thing first and get things done.</p><p>When we prioritize the most valuable tasks over all the ‘busywork’ tasks, that is when we effectively improve our productivity. That is how we will be able to achieve much more in much less time. Everyone has the same amount of time, 24 hours per day, get more done in less time is the key.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;If let me think about the busiest person in the world, I immediately think of Elon Musk. How he can get so many things done every single 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Taking a risk or not taking</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/09/27/taking-a-risk-or-not-taking/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/09/27/taking-a-risk-or-not-taking/</id>
    <published>2020-09-27T05:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-09-27T06:54:03.275Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It is common to hear the advice that people should take some risk and uncertainty if they want to be successful. Risk can separate into two different types, calculated risk, and non-calculated risk. I think knowing what you do and taking a risk with knowledge is calculated risk. When you have the knowledge of the things you are doing, you can handle the uncertainty, you can calculate the risk.</p><p>However, does risk-taking can lead to success or it is essential to be successful? For me, the answer depends on several factors, different people doing the same thing can lead to a different result. Successful people tend to take risks in ways that limit their potential losses.</p><blockquote><p>Entrepreneurs are not risk takers. They are calculated risk takers. - Leonard C. Green</p></blockquote><p>“The difference between risk-takers and calculated risk-takers is the difference between failure and success,” Green said. To be honest, this ideal looks like a survivorship bias, when the risk-taker becomes successful, we will think this is a good risk to take, but when the risk-taker becomes a failure, we will think this is a bad risk. In order to avoid survivorship bias, we need to look at the same thing in different ways and different perspectives. Take some time to study to get knowledge, we should look at the failure case, it is way more important than look at the success case. When we have the knowledge, we know how to play the game and applying some strategies.</p><p>Risk-taking does have some relative with success, but there are too many complicated factors to say that taking the risk will increase your chances to become successful. Even though those successful people also need to find ways to mitigate damage and lower the risks they take.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;It is common to hear the advice that people should take some risk and uncertainty if they want to be successful. Risk can separate into t
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Be responsible for your future self</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/09/18/be-responsible-for-your-future-self/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/09/18/be-responsible-for-your-future-self/</id>
    <published>2020-09-18T06:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-09-18T11:58:44.026Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When you think about how you will become in the future, who you will be in the future, and you look at your present and future selves as two different people. What you need to do to become the person you desire to be, the things that you doing now will benefit your future self. This is an important question that we need to ask ourselves, it is essential for our self-growth and become a better person.</p><p>Visualize about the future negative consequences that your future self will experience, what skill is required to overcome these negative moments, it can be a positive mindset or mentally strong heart, experiencing more things will make us stronger. Keep trying new things and learn from it is the key, the more you know the more you realize you don’t know. Go through all the things that happened in our life, good things or bad things all are valuable. Taking responsibility when you screw up, admit our mistake is the first step to conquer it.</p><blockquote><p>Remember that everything is a case study. Think about what it is a case of and what principles apply. - Ray Dalio</p></blockquote><p>Change only comes from taking action not just knowing about it. Every time we realize we need to do something for our future self, we need to take immediate action on it, I know sometimes it can be tough though.</p><p>The way you do anything is the way you do everything, we should start from a very tiny step on small things that can keep improving ourselves, it could be just a 5 mins exercise every day, but it will make a big impact in our life. Start building a new habit for future self, give them a healthy life, they will be grateful for us in taking these minor actions.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;When you think about how you will become in the future, who you will be in the future, and you look at your present and future selves as 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Opportunities in times of crisis</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/09/12/opportunities-in-times-of-crisis/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/09/12/opportunities-in-times-of-crisis/</id>
    <published>2020-09-12T14:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-09-12T15:46:00.101Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Whenever something bad happened, it may make someone worst or there could be an opportunity for someone to get better. Everything has two sides, everything has its advantages and disadvantages. Crisis entails opportunities, we should try to look at the other side to avoid bias, though it is not easy but doable.</p><p>During this pandemic, a lot of people start doing digital marketing, they saw other people are doing something, so they also want to follow the trend, but this fall into the herd mentality, people can be influenced by their peers to adopt certain behaviors.</p><blockquote><p>It’s not the strongest of the species that survives, nor the most intelligent, but the one most adaptable to change. - Charles Darwin</p></blockquote><p>Should we follow other people doing the same things to avoid falling behind, or should we accommodate ourselves to adopt the new changes in the environment, I prefer the second one. When we follow the trend, doing the same things as other people doing, we are stuck in the 80% crowd, we can’t stand out in this situation. </p><p>The other option is don’t follow other people but improve ourselves to stay in the game, learning new skills that essential to survive in the environment. I think this is better than following other people back since we are growing with new experiences and it doesn’t hurt to trying new things. Even though step out of our comfort zone and overcome the challenges in a new environment is not easy, we are taking a risk and opening ourselves up to the possibility of stress, it will be tough but it is worth spending effort on it.</p><p>Even if I fail now, the skills I have acquiring will be valuable in the future, it will become my weapon to fight the next challenges.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Whenever something bad happened, it may make someone worst or there could be an opportunity for someone to get better. Everything has two
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Good person won&#39;t necessarily to become successful</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/09/05/good-person-won-t-necessarily-to-become-successful/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/09/05/good-person-won-t-necessarily-to-become-successful/</id>
    <published>2020-09-05T15:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-09-05T16:11:53.191Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes we thought we have to be knowledgeable to become successful, but in fact, not all the professors or scientists they can achieve success in life, even though they study a lot. Sometimes we thought we need to be hardworking to become successful but in fact, most of the foreign workers can’t achieve success in life, even though they are very hardworking on their work.</p><p>When I look at a successful person who has some disadvantages, I’m thinking about how he or she can be successful with such defeats. They could be being rude or be emotional with someone, how they can achieve success with doing such bad things, why we being a good person but can’t achieve something in our life. Though I still suffering in this thinking, but I realized that no one is saying that being a good person definitely can be a success in life. We still need to put hard work on something that we really desired to achieve, being a good person is just a choice as a human, although it’s not easy being kind all the time.</p><blockquote><p>The real test is being kind to unkind people. - Unknown</p></blockquote><p>Successful people can be unkind people. Nobody is perfect, people can be successful in their careers but fail in personal life, people can be kind in their family but doesn’t look successful in other people’s perspectives.</p><p>Good person won’t necessarily to become successful. I think the point here is not about being a good person or a bad person. The point here is how we determine success, it could be a different thing in different people’s life. However, keep improving ourselves to become better is essential to become successful, nobody is keeping the worst to achieve success. Fortunately, life is not fair but it is still good.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Sometimes we thought we have to be knowledgeable to become successful, but in fact, not all the professors or scientists they can achieve
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
