<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Jeffrey H.</title>
  
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/"/>
  <updated>2020-05-30T14:26:16.262Z</updated>
  <id>https://thejeffrey.me/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Jeffrey H.</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Production stock take in a manufacturing company</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/05/30/production-stock-take-in-a-manufacturing-company/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/05/30/production-stock-take-in-a-manufacturing-company/</id>
    <published>2020-05-30T14:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-30T14:26:16.262Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In Panasonic Senai, we have a department managing the raw material for the production lines, they control the material that needed in the production to ensure the production lines can run smoothly. They have to work with Store members to prepare the raw material followed by the production plan, all the material will move to the production warehouse from the Store warehouse.</p><p>Before production lines start running and produce finish goods, they follow the material listing to collect all the raw materials needed for the production, each product has at least 20 raw materials. They need to collect and count the material carefully since different material has a different quantity for each type of product, they need to follow the material listing and production plan and split it into multiple production lines. Sometimes there have some quality issues in the production line that running haft way, they need to stop the production and collect back all the raw material and put the balance back to the production warehouse. These business processes are involved in a lot of manual processes and it costs a lot of manpower. In order to enhance these processes, top management requested the IT department to implement a system to optimize it.</p><p>When our department working on this project, I had been assigned to join in and support the implementation. After we study and understand the whole process, we implemented some new processes for them to work with the system to reduce the workload and prevent human error, instead of doing everything in manual ways. They can download the enhanced material listing that auto-generate with production plans and production lines. We also implement the QR code system to help them to collect material and manage production warehouse. This system can reduce around 50% of the workload and prevent inventory discrepancies. They do the stock check with more efficiently and accurately, they increate the stock check routine to weekly from twice a month. However, in the beginning, we need to put a lot of effort to implement it, design the layout, printout the QR code, and allocate it one by one.</p><p>This is a huge change for them, they need to adapt to the new process and change their working habit, this is not easy for them since they are used to the old manual process, they need to be open-minded to accept the new things that can improve their workload.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;In Panasonic Senai, we have a department managing the raw material for the production lines, they control the material that needed in the
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="experience" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/experience/"/>
    
      <category term="B2B" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/B2B/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Production planning in a manufacturing company</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/05/24/production-planning-in-a-manufacturing-company/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/05/24/production-planning-in-a-manufacturing-company/</id>
    <published>2020-05-24T15:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-24T16:36:15.985Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I was working in Panasonic Senai, back than 2016, the production planning department is such a huge and complicated department around one hundred staff, they are managing production plans, raw material plans, delivery plans, shipment plans, and all the production products. The complicated part is they need to cooperate with multiple parties, members from other departments, and outside vendors, they need to ensure the production line can run smoothly. This business process runs a highly important part of a manufacturing company.</p><p>Everything starts from the Sales Order. They receive the Sales Order from Panasonic Japan with the target shipment date, normally they will receive the order 6 months in advance. They need to calculate the raw material from the required products to start planning the production. They contact the suppliers of the raw material and manage the estimated delivery date, so they can start planing the production line and arrange production shifts. After that, they need to work with the Logistics member for the shipment date and reply estimated arrived date to customers. </p><p>Plans always fall behind changes. Sometime the production plan will be affected by multiple issues such as delayed material delivery, production quality control issues, etc. They need to respond immediately and roll out a new production plan to prevent the delay of arriving in customers, like fire fighting. There are a lot of complicated processes and manual works.</p><p>In order to optimize the business process and prevent human error, we control most of the processes in our ERP system, SAP. Most of the documents will go through the system and connect with vendors and suppliers, but they still need to do human decisions like production planning and forecast. I had been assigned to create a system for them with the production forecast planning. This system will collect all the Sales Order and the raw material dataset to calculate and forecast the production plan. It also connects with the Inventory system to highlight the material shortage in a dashboard, so they can easy to monitor the raw material with the production plan.</p><p>I got this opportunity to study and understand the production business process, this is a rare experience for me and I can’t easily learn about it from other companies, this experience brings me forward in my career.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;When I was working in Panasonic Senai, back than 2016, the production planning department is such a huge and complicated department aroun
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="experience" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/experience/"/>
    
      <category term="B2B" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/B2B/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Repair Service in a manufacturing company</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/05/16/repair-service-in-a-manufacturing-company/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/05/16/repair-service-in-a-manufacturing-company/</id>
    <published>2020-05-16T14:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-16T15:11:59.196Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I working in Panasonic Senai, we have a department by the name of C&amp;R, C&amp;R stands for Configuration and Repair. They are doing a repair service for the end-user who using the Panasonic laptop. Most of the customers have come from Panasonic Singapore or other corporate end-user. This repair service business model has good potential since Panasonic Taiwan is the only main provider in Asia. Previously, this Repair Service is provided by Panasonic Singapore, but due to the high labor costs, we try to undertake this business since we have an unfair advantage in the operation costs. Panasonic Singapore also agrees to move their customers to us.</p><p>Panasonic Senai becomes the window person who provides repair service. Customers ship their device to us by post service and C&amp;R members will receive it and start doing their operation. They have to record down all the serial numbers of the devices to prevent miss-match with the wrong customer. After they complete the diagnosis of device and feedback to the customer if they wanted to repair or send back to them. C&amp;R member has to check the warranty information if the device is still under warranty or the device was configured by the C&amp;R Configuration team. There are some complicated workflows involved in human processes. They have to do diagnosing with following the documentation and instruction provider by Panasonic Japan. They have to handle customer service and feedback, sometimes they have the warranty issues in the system.</p><p>We implemented a system to assist them to manage all the business processes, everything will log in system, so this will enhance the traceability of their repair jobs. This system will help them to control the goods-in and goods-out process to prevent human error. Since their repair parts can share with the Configuration team, we implement inventory management in the system and forecast the usage of the repair parts, this will help them on the inventory purchase request. This process will reduce the customer waiting time when their repair part is not available.</p><p>This system was developed by Japan members but handover to me to maintain it. I also do the enhancement with C&amp;R members to improve the business process and reduce operator workload. This gave me a good opportunity to learn new things and improve myself.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;When I working in Panasonic Senai, we have a department by the name of C&amp;amp;R, C&amp;amp;R stands for Configuration and Repair. They are doi
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="experience" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/experience/"/>
    
      <category term="B2B" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/B2B/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Configuration Business in a manufacturing company</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/05/08/configuration-business-in-a-manufacturing-company/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/05/08/configuration-business-in-a-manufacturing-company/</id>
    <published>2020-05-08T14:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-08T15:41:54.081Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back then in 2016, I was working in Panasonic Senai for about one year. My company just started a new department with a new business modal which is C&amp;R, C&amp;R stands for Configuration and Repair. This business is focused on support Panasonic’s laptop and tablet which are TOUGHBOOK and TOUGHPAD. They do the customize configuration for the new devices such as install GPS sensors or upgrade software and OS. And the repair team will focus on repair customer’s TOUGHBOOK such as hardware that broken or spoilt. </p><p>There is a huge demand from oversea counties like the UK and the US. Panasonic in the UK has a company which doing the same thing as C&amp;R but the labor costs are very high, so we have the cost advantage in Malaysia. Most of the new devices are produced in Taiwan, then they will ship to us and do configuration before send out to customers.</p><p>The complicated part of this business is in the inventory. Since we can’t stock all the configuration parts and devices, so we have to keep track of the Sales Order to do the forecast for goods requests and orders. C&amp;R members have to make sure all the parts are getting ready on time when the devices have arrived and start doing configuration immediately and ship out in short timing. </p><p>This business was authorized by Panasonic Japan, they sent some people from Japan to here to set up the production environment and give training for C&amp;R members. C&amp;R members have to follow the SOP that given by Japan and follow the documentation for each operation.</p><p>We also have a new system developed by Japan members and implemented in C&amp;R, this system will help us to manage all the production process and workflow. I had been assigned to maintain this system and do the enhancement on our own, so I have to fully understand the whole business process in each workflow. </p><p>This allowed me to learn something new from Japan members and the business model that is not often seen in the market.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Back then in 2016, I was working in Panasonic Senai for about one year. My company just started a new department with a new business moda
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="experience" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/experience/"/>
    
      <category term="B2B" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/B2B/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Logistics in a manufacturing company</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/05/02/logistics-in-a-manufacturing-company/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/05/02/logistics-in-a-manufacturing-company/</id>
    <published>2020-05-02T15:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-08T15:31:01.816Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I working in Panasonic Senai, there is a department by the name of Logistics. The Logistics department is mainly working on shipping and delivery. Most of the time they are busy arranging shipment for finished products which ship to oversea. Overall orders are come from Panasonic Japan but shipped out to customers in the US and UK. The job scope of the Logistics department is organizing the deal date of orders with shipment date, they have to work closely with the Production department and the vendors for shipment. </p><p>The common problems that happen in the Logistics department are redundant processes, inaccurate inventory layout, and lack of efficiency. They need a system to help them to reduce high labor costs and prevent human error. In Panasonic Senai, all the Sales Order and Shipping Instruction are going through our ERP system. Logistics members can do the planning, forecast, and manage shipment with the system and work more efficiently. However, for the physical goods, they need a good facility layout and spaces to manage the packing process, therefore we implement a system to resolve this issue.</p><p>As a software engineer in the Information System Department, I have the opportunity to join in the project to study the whole process and design the solution called Pallet Checker System. This system is a helper that works with members when they do the packing process. Members have to scan all the products during warping, pallet by pallet. It can ensure the packed finished products are matched with Shipping Instruction so that we are not sending the wrong product to the wrong customer. This system also enhances the storage shortage issue with the scheduled shipment that needs to be ship out on time.</p><p>This is a fresh experience for me since I never study the process of Sales Order and Shipping Instruction, this project helps me a lot to gain new exposure in the manufacturing business process. </p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;When I working in Panasonic Senai, there is a department by the name of Logistics. The Logistics department is mainly working on shipping
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="experience" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/experience/"/>
    
      <category term="B2B" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/B2B/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Corporate Purchase in a manufacturing company</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/04/25/corporate-purchase-in-a-manufacturing-company/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/04/25/corporate-purchase-in-a-manufacturing-company/</id>
    <published>2020-04-25T13:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-08T15:31:04.092Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back then, 2017, when I working in Panasonic Senai. Our factory has a department named Corporate Purchase, all the members in this department who will be handling raw materials and finished goods, so-called Inbound and Outbound. It is a very complex process with cumbersome workflow, every member had to cooperate with other departments. For the material purchasing team, they had to work with vendors to ensure all the material can arrive on time. For the finished goods team, they had to work with the Logistics department to make sure the goods can be ship out on schedule. In order to manage this huge workflow and improve their work efficiency, they need an Inventory System to enhance their workflows.</p><p>As a software engineer in the Information System Department, I have the opportunity to join in this project with my manager and senior manager to implement an Inventory System. The goal of this system is to reduce their workload and prevent human error in their process. To achieve this target, we have to study the whole process and understand the details in each workflow. </p><p>In the inbound delivery process, when the raw materials came in, store members have to verify the item and check the quantity is correct, update it in system and move into the warehouse. This is a heavy-duty workload and it can cause a lot of human error. Therefore, we implement a barcode system to help them to manage the stock and improve traceability in goods movement.</p><p>In the outbound delivery process, when the finished goods had been done packing, store members have to move the finished goods to the Logistics department to do the shipment, pallet by pallet. In order to operate smoothly with each department, we have to implement a system to manage this workflow and conduct the process.</p><p>This project brings me a chance to broaden my horizons, I learned a lot of different things from my field, and get the experiment to work in a multi-channel group. </p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Back then, 2017, when I working in Panasonic Senai. Our factory has a department named Corporate Purchase, all the members in this depart
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="experience" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/experience/"/>
    
      <category term="B2B" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/B2B/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Leanstack - Ash Maurya (Part 2)</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/04/18/leanstack-ash-maurya-part-2/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/04/18/leanstack-ash-maurya-part-2/</id>
    <published>2020-04-18T14:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-04-18T15:59:49.465Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol start="6"><li>Prioritize Your Riskiest Assumptions</li></ol><p>Since startups are inherently risky, it follows that the best strategy for protecting the downside is prioritizing the riskiest. If we apply stress to the chain, it will break at its weakest link. We have to find out the weaknesses of the business model and the risky part so that we can avoid the chance of failure. Focus on the riskiest, settle the hardest part as a priority, it is very tough at the beginning but it will help us afterward.</p><ol start="7"><li>Think 10X</li></ol><p>A thousand miles begins with a single step. All businesses are started with one customer, they then grow to at least 10 customers, and most likely 100 customers, that’s two 10X jumps right there. Sometimes we are overthinking and scaled too early. We can have a growth strategy but it must be reasonable, we have to understand the reality and know where we are. Focus on traction instead of revenue or profit.</p><ol start="8"><li>Make Evidence Driven Decisions</li></ol><p>From plan A to a plan that works before running out of resources. We can systematically test our models and plans using small and fast experiments that stress testes the riskiest assumptions.</p><p>Two types of experiments:</p><p>Discovery experiments: interviewing customers to understand their problems.<br>Throughput experiments:  measuring traction, measuring changes in customer behavior towards a new feature.</p><p>We have to seek feedback from customers. When we looking at a business from an individual perspective, it is not accurate since it can have a lot of bias. Here is some advice to avoid this matter:<br>Source a diversity of ideas: good ideas can come from anywhere, we can diverse sets of possible solutions to a problem, it can from a designer or marketer.<br>Rank your ideas: finding a shortlist of solutions, deliver the biggest impact for the least amount of effort.<br>Test your idea: run a throughput experiment to test the selected idea, if it increases in traction then continue on it.</p><ol start="9"><li>Validate Qualitatively, Verify Quantitatively</li></ol><p>If we launch a landing page and the conversion isn’t great, we can systematically change it and retest the landing page. But fixing issues can take a long time, we have to throughput an experiment and measure the amount of effort.</p><ol start="10"><li>Remove Failure From Your Vocabulary</li></ol><p>As a scientist, many discoveries started as failed experiments. But instead of throwing away their “failed” experiments. they did something very different from most people; they asked why. Breakthrough insights are often hidden within failed experiments. Before we can find a business model that works, we have to go through lots of stuff that doesn’t work. The taboo of failure runs so deep, we have to understand the realities and admit our failure, we have to accept our weaknesses and improve on it, accept failure as a prerequisite to achieving the breakthrough.</p><blockquote><p>There is no such thing as a failed experiment, only experiments with unexpected outcomes. - Buckminster Fuller</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;ol start=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prioritize Your Riskiest Assumptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since startups are inherently risky, it follows that the best strategy
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="leanstack" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/leanstack/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Leanstack - Ash Maurya (Part 1)</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/04/11/leanstack-ash-maurya-part-1/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/04/11/leanstack-ash-maurya-part-1/</id>
    <published>2020-04-11T15:20:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-04-11T16:34:16.551Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol><li>Love the Problem, Not Your Solution</li></ol><p>People spending effort to build something nobody wants. A lot of people they are thinking about their idea is very good and start to build it immediately without finding the customer, they never do research about the market and find out their potential customers. Customers don’t care about your solutions, they care about their problems, no matter how great your product is. Traditionally, people building a key without a door, then try to figure out what door to open. But a better alternative is switch perspective, start with understanding a problem before building a solution, this becomes a lot easier after that.</p><blockquote><p>A problem well-defined is a problem half-solved. - Charles Kettring</p></blockquote><ol start="2"><li>The Business Model is the Product</li></ol><p>Market * Product = Profit</p><p>We need to ensure we have a problem that worth to solve and it’s monetizable from the customer’s pain point. Entrepreneur not just building a solution to a problem, but building a working business model is more important. Scientists use models to simplify a problem, make predictions and validated through experiments. Entrepreneur can do the same with business models. A good business model can create value for customers by solving a problem they wanted to solve.</p><ol start="3"><li>Traction is the Goal</li></ol><p>Traction is tempting to measure a working business model in terms of revenue or profit. It can be the rate of a business that captures monetizable value from its customers. We can show the growth in traction to get attention from investors. We can find an example from Facebook, it is a social media platform but captures value from advertisers who buy attention and data. Daily active users (DAU) can predict future revenue from advertisers, this is what called Traction.</p><ol start="4"><li>Right Action, Right Time</li></ol><p>Most of the entrepreneurs are trying to go fast on everything. But going fast on everything doesn’t necessarily make us go faster. Sometimes we wanted to get everything done but we didn’t think about which one is the priority or which one is most valuable. We try to optimize our product when we have no customers. We try to raise funding without any traction. The goal of entrepreneur is to find a business model that works before running out of resources. Time is the scarcest resource compare with others, we waste a lot of time to build a perfect product that no customer wants.</p><ol start="5"><li>Give Yourself Permission to Scale</li></ol><p>Three specific stages in a hockey-stick curve in the product lifecycle also known as Traction.</p><blockquote><p>Problem / Solution Fit  -&gt;  Product / Market Fit  -&gt;  Scale</p></blockquote><p>Problem / Solution Fit: Finding a problem worth solving, get paying customers without having to first build out a fully functioning solution.</p><p>Problem / Market Fit: Demonstrating a working business model with just a few good customers. A minimum viable product can test your business model fast and without wasting resources.</p><p>Scale: Once we have repeatability in a working business model, we can shifting focus to growth. We can test the full potential of a business model by scaling a product to support multi types of customers.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love the Problem, Not Your Solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People spending effort to build something nobody wants. A lot of people they are 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="leanstack" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/leanstack/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Purchase Request in a manufacturing company</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/04/04/purchase-request-in-a-manufacturing-company/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/04/04/purchase-request-in-a-manufacturing-company/</id>
    <published>2020-04-04T15:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-08T15:31:09.452Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been working in a manufacturing company (Panasonic) as an in-house software developer. The scopes of in-house software are supporting internal business workflows, improve productivity and increase product quality. Since all software is used by our employees, so as a software developer, I have to understand our company’s business workflows and what are they doing in each department.</p><p>I still can remember when I had been assigned to support a Purchase Request system. I have to work with the Corporate Purchasing Department. I did the feasibility study of purchasing workflow. It is quite a complicated workflow involved clerk, purchaser, administrator, and vendor. A purchase request basically can split into two categories which are Regular Request and Ad-hoc Request. The Regular Request is repeatable every week or every month, so it has a fixed vendor. The Ad-hoc Request is a special request like ordering a machine or purchase a service. The ad-hoc request needs management to approve and get acknowledgment.</p><p>In order to get a clear idea of the process, I have to follow the purchaser run through the whole process, like a clerk submit a request form to request purchase, the administrator verifies the request and gets approval from management. Finance has to approve the request then the purchaser submits a purchase order to the vendor and gets the delivery timeline from the vendor. Each of the workflows needed a clear vision and well designed in the system.</p><p>I realized that every department is working as a chain that links with each other. It required a lot of communication and good cooperation between each employee. As a software developer, I have to communicate with people coming from different backgrounds, get experience from them and sometimes I have to learn how to convince them when needed.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;I have been working in a manufacturing company (Panasonic) as an in-house software developer. The scopes of in-house software are support
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="experience" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/experience/"/>
    
      <category term="B2B" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/B2B/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Accept new things</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/03/29/accept-new-things/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/03/29/accept-new-things/</id>
    <published>2020-03-29T15:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-29T17:02:59.032Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back then, I was working in Panasonic Senai, our top management is looking for an inventory system since our members are doing in a manual way of inventory management that lasted 30 years. They manual verify incoming material and manually enter all data into our ERP system which is SAP system. They manual do the stock check with human counting twice a month. These manual ways of working brought about human errors, inefficiency business processes, and cheating in goods lost. These are big problem for our company, it’s very hard to manage and affect our company’s profit.</p><p>As a software engineer in Panasonic Senai, I was involved in this project to study the current issues and come out with a solution. We make a comparison between in-house development and outsource development. In-house development can save costs but outsource development can save time. After a few discussions with our department manager and top management. Finally, they decided to assign the development to the outsourcing company but we have to maintain and enhance the system in the future. This project was assigned to an outsourcing company which is Deloitte. Deloitte is a UK company and they have a lot of professional SAP consultants, that’s why this project took around one million Ringgit Malaysia and implemented within 6 months.</p><p>Unfortunately, it happens a lot of issues after implement this system. Our members were frustrated with this new system since they think this new system does not help them to reduce their works but brings more works to them. However, this new system is a good practice and it can help them to prevent human error. I found out that they were frustrated because they didn’t want to accept new things and new workflows. It is a big impact on them as they felt very comfortable in their current workflows and they felt very hard to adapt to new technologies. It is a mindset issue that has to solve on mindset, not the system.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Back then, I was working in Panasonic Senai, our top management is looking for an inventory system since our members are doing in a manua
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Luck Surface Area</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/03/21/luck-surface-area/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/03/21/luck-surface-area/</id>
    <published>2020-03-21T15:35:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-21T17:41:11.022Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>You make your own luck - Jason Roberts</p></blockquote><p>How do you increase your chance of success? Your “Luck Surface Area” can help you. This is a term coined by Jason Roberts in a 2010 blog post. When the first time I saw this term I felt shocked, I did not know luck can have a surface area and you can control the amount of luck that you receive. </p><p>As I understand it, when you contribute something and people aware of it, you will get more opportunities. When you pour energy into a passion, you become an expert in one field, somebody will look for you. This idea does match my belief. I’ve always thought about learn more things and do more work will lead me to wider possibilities. When you do something you are passionate about and do something is valuable, people will feel interested and try to capture that value. When people need you more than you need people, you started to be valuable. </p><p><img src="/images/luck-surface-area.png" alt="Luck Surface Area" title="Luck Surface Area"></p><p>This is the graphical representation that really brings the concept home. However, I does not like the word “tell” in here instead of “aware”. Cause I think let people aware of your value is better than tell people what you have, it is harder to achieve though.</p><p>Although, how to make people aware of your value is a big question, it can be a long journey. Even though you are an expert in doing something but people do not aware of it, it will become nothing. Let others know of your worth are equally important and commonly be overlooked.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You make your own luck - Jason Roberts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you increase your chance of success? Your “Luck Surface A
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Working in Panasonic Senai</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/03/14/working-in-panasonic-senai/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/03/14/working-in-panasonic-senai/</id>
    <published>2020-03-14T15:05:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-21T17:25:54.167Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I join Panasonic Senai as a software technician in 2015, my starting salary was only RM1600 and after 3 months of probation, it becomes RM1650. This is quite a low salary but I felt excited went to work every day since I knew this is just temporary. I knew I can earn more salary in the future when I got more working experience.</p><p>Panasonic Senai is a manufacturer that produces telephone machines and fax machines with employed around 1000 employees including foreign workers. In Infomation System Department, we have 2 teams which are Infra team and Software team. I’m working in the Software team with 5 colleagues. In the beginning, my manager was led me to join the existing projects and understand the company’s system structure. Our team was assigned to support all in-house systems so I have to cooperate with other colleagues from other departments. I have to understand what are they doing and how the system can solve their problems. I found that it’s a big difference in actual working experience compare with what I learned in theory before.</p><p>After 3 months I was assigned to run a small project alone. It’s a booking system for book meeting rooms. Before I started this project, people who want to book a meeting room have to manage in an excel file which allocated in a shared folder. It’s very hard to check daily appointments and people have to calculate the available time manually. Sometimes people will accidentally remove or edited other people’s bookings. So I planed and developed a web application to solve these issues, it’s a calendar-based application, people can check and make a booking with a user-friendly interface.</p><p>One day I saw a colleague using this application to easily manage her booking and she told me it’s a very useful application. This is the first time I saw people using an application that developed by me, it’s an impressing feeling, I felt blessed to doing this.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;When I join Panasonic Senai as a software technician in 2015, my starting salary was only RM1600 and after 3 months of probation, it beco
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>First step in my career</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/03/08/first-step-in-my-career/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/03/08/first-step-in-my-career/</id>
    <published>2020-03-08T14:50:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-14T14:24:18.923Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back then, I was a Diploma graduate in 2015 who was young, dumb and broke. In Johor Bahru, people will always talk about working in Singapore since it’s just a bridge away and earning Singapore dollars is much more lucrative due to the high currency exchange rates. I feel like want to work in Singapore also to earn SGD since the currency exchange rate was 1SGD to 2.6RM at that moment.<br>However, I have zero working experience in my career as a software engineer. I believe it will be very hard to get a job for me as a foreign worker, so I decided to work in Johor Bahru to gain more experience and improve myself.</p><p>During my job search, my classmate got a job in a Malay company as a junior developer and he recommended me to join this company, so I went to an interview with his manager and successfully got a job offer with RM1200 monthly salary and the CEO also offer me to work in another branch in Kuala Lumpur. RM1200 is very low salary since the average for a fresh graduate student is RM1800 in JB, RM2200 in KL. At that time I felt like I needed more working experience so I accepted the job offer and start working immediately in JB.</p><p>We need to work on Sunday, take off on Friday and Saturday since it’s a Malay company and I’m the only Chinese in whole company, so I have to accept the different culture. I can still remember that moment when my colleagues all go “sembahyang” pray twice a day during working hours, I’m the only one who stayed in office with no one else. However I’m still good with my colleagues and learned a lot from them.</p><p>Unfortunately, I quit this company after 3 days but I still learned a lot. I saw that a government project has the potential to make billions of Ringgit. I felt like it’s very hard to accept their culture and I don’t like their project planning, every time have to do OT to rush their project timeline, luckily I did not accept the job offer that required me to move to KL.</p><p>Sometimes misfortune can actually be a blessing, I moved forward in my career and join another company, Panasonic.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Back then, I was a Diploma graduate in 2015 who was young, dumb and broke. In Johor Bahru, people will always talk about working in Singa
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>unix</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2016/04/29/unix/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2016/04/29/unix/</id>
    <published>2016-04-29T01:26:13.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-05-02T06:31:04.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>ufw</p><p>sudo apt-get install ufw</p><p>sudo ufw enable<br>sudo ufw allow ssh<br>sudo ufw allow 22<br>sudo ufw allow http<br>sudo ufw allow https<br>sudo ufw allow 3000</p><p>sudo ufw deny http</p><p>sudo ufw status</p><p>$ vi /etc/ssh/sshd_config</p><p>PermitRootLogin no<br>PubkeyAuthentication no<br>AllowUsers ramesh john jason<br>Port 222</p><p>server timezone</p><p>sudo dpkg-reconfigure tzdata</p><p>Filter for brute-force interactive SSH logins<br>grep sshd.*Failed /var/log/auth.log | less</p><p>Look for failed connections (i.e. no login attempted, could be a port scanner, etc.):<br>grep sshd.*Did /var/log/auth.log | less</p><p>sudo apt-get install fail2ban</p><p>/etc/apache2/pache2.conf</p>&lt;Directory /var/www/&gt;<br>    Options Indexes FollowSymLinks<br>    AllowOverride All<br>    Require all granted<br></Directory><p>sudo a2enmod rewrite<br>sudo service apache2 restart</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;ufw&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get install ufw&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sudo ufw enable&lt;br&gt;sudo ufw allow ssh&lt;br&gt;sudo ufw allow 22&lt;br&gt;sudo ufw allow http&lt;br&gt;sudo ufw 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="unix" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/unix/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>hexo</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2016/04/29/hexo/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2016/04/29/hexo/</id>
    <published>2016-04-29T01:21:34.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-05-05T14:17:26.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="hexo-3"><a href="#hexo-3" class="headerlink" title="hexo 3"></a>hexo 3</h1><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">hexo clean</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">hexo generate / hexo g</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">hexo deploy / hexo d</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Short cut:<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">hexo g -d</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p><h2 id="Static-Sidebar"><a href="#Static-Sidebar" class="headerlink" title="Static Sidebar"></a>Static Sidebar</h2><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">grep -rl <span class="string">'displaySidebar'</span> themes/next/</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h3 id="comment-the-code"><a href="#comment-the-code" class="headerlink" title="comment the code"></a>comment the code</h3><p>themes/next/source/js/src/motion.js<br><figure class="highlight js"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">sidebar: <span class="function"><span class="keyword">function</span> (<span class="params">integrator</span>) </span>&#123;</span><br><span class="line">  <span class="comment">//if (CONFIG.sidebar.display === 'always') &#123;</span></span><br><span class="line">    NexT.utils.displaySidebar();</span><br><span class="line">  <span class="comment">//&#125;</span></span><br><span class="line">  integrator.next();</span><br><span class="line">&#125;</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p><p>themes/next/source/js/src/post-details.js<br><figure class="highlight js"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">NexT.motion.middleWares.sidebar = <span class="function"><span class="keyword">function</span> (<span class="params"></span>) </span>&#123;</span><br><span class="line">    <span class="keyword">var</span> $tocContent = $(<span class="string">'.post-toc-content'</span>);</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">    <span class="comment">//if (CONFIG.sidebar.display === 'post' || CONFIG.sidebar.display === 'always') &#123;</span></span><br><span class="line">      <span class="keyword">if</span> ($tocContent.length &gt; <span class="number">0</span> &amp;&amp; $tocContent.html().trim().length &gt; <span class="number">0</span>) &#123;</span><br><span class="line">        NexT.utils.displaySidebar();</span><br><span class="line">      &#125;</span><br><span class="line">    <span class="comment">//&#125;</span></span><br><span class="line">&#125;;</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">hexo g -d</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h2 id="add-on-for-hexo"><a href="#add-on-for-hexo" class="headerlink" title="add-on for hexo"></a>add-on for hexo</h2><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">npm install hexo-generator-feed --save</span><br><span class="line">npm install hexo-generator-sitemap@1.0.0 --save</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>__dir/_config.yml<br><figure class="highlight yml"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="attr">theme:</span> <span class="string">next</span></span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">sitemap:</span></span><br><span class="line">  <span class="attr">path:</span> <span class="string">sitemap.xml</span></span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">feed:</span></span><br><span class="line">  <span class="attr">path:</span> <span class="string">atom.xml</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">npm update</span><br><span class="line">hexo g -d</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h2 id="NexT-theme"><a href="#NexT-theme" class="headerlink" title="NexT theme"></a>NexT theme</h2><figure class="highlight js"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"># Schemes</span><br><span class="line">scheme: Muse</span><br><span class="line"># Sidebar</span><br><span class="line">display: always</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">avatar:</span><br><span class="line">  /images/avatar.png</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">highlight_theme: night eighties</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">hexo clean</span><br><span class="line">hexo g -d</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">hexo new page <span class="string">"tags"</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>tags\index.md<br><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">title: All tags</span><br><span class="line">date: 2014-12-22 12:39:04</span><br><span class="line">type: &quot;tags&quot;</span><br><span class="line">---</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p><p>themes/_config.yml<br><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">menu:</span><br><span class="line">  home: &#x2F;</span><br><span class="line">  archives: &#x2F;archives</span><br><span class="line">  tags: &#x2F;tags</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;hexo-3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#hexo-3&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;hexo 3&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;hexo 3&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight bash&quot;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutt
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="hexo" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/hexo/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
