<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Jeffrey H.</title>
  
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/"/>
  <updated>2021-04-04T15:59:50.559Z</updated>
  <id>https://thejeffrey.me/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Jeffrey H.</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Morning peak time of productivity</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2021/04/04/morning-peak-time-of-productivity/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2021/04/04/morning-peak-time-of-productivity/</id>
    <published>2021-04-04T13:50:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-04-04T15:59:50.559Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>According to research, most people are most efficient during the first two hours of the morning. The morning is often the peak time of productivity. Most people tend to be energetic, focused, and clear-minded. The disciplined people use the morning time to knock down the one most high-impact task that is the most complex and intimidating.</p><p>There are several key benefits to starting our most important task early in the morning. Firstly, when we completed the most energy-draining task in the day, the rest of the day feels like fulfilled. The day is pretty much a big success before the afternoon. Secondly, the use of this rule can prevent us from delaying the tasks that have the greatest impact on our goals and make the most progress.</p><p>Usually, we tend to delay on important tasks because these tasks are very complex and energy-consuming. They are always put off until tomorrow and the future. However, if we try to set at least one priority before the afternoon, we can no longer procrastinate on the tasks anymore.</p><p>Because the most important tasks require our 100% attention, it is good practice to use the morning peak hours to complete one of the tasks instead of doing paperwork, replying to messages, or answering emails.</p><blockquote><p>If you want to get the most out of your day, do your most important work “your one thing” early. - Gary Keller</p></blockquote><p>I try my best to make full use of the peak hours in the morning to complete the most important task of the day. At this moment, my mind is the clearest, my attention is the most concentrated, and mental clarity. When I try to do this in the afternoon, I just struggle to stay focused and it requires more energy consumption.</p><p>After completing the high-impact tasks before the afternoon, I gain a sense of accomplishment and motivation for the rest of the day.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;According to research, most people are most efficient during the first two hours of the morning. The morning is often the peak time of pr
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="productivity" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/productivity/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Proud of being busy?</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2021/03/27/proud-of-being-busy/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2021/03/27/proud-of-being-busy/</id>
    <published>2021-03-27T15:55:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-27T17:28:04.074Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nowadays, people are going to cultivate the habit of celebrating busyness. Most people are proud of being busy, just like having an honor badge on it. People think as long as we are doing a lot of things mean that we can expect to achieve success. I think it is interesting to see how some people block the productivity they seek. Those who aggressively run around all day to be the busiest, which is usually rewarded with compliments and promotion. </p><p>However, I think this is the wrong thing to be proud of and nothing to celebrate. Being busy does not mean being productive. Being busy has nothing to do with bringing in value. People who are busy running around all day have nothing to do with making progress towards the most important tasks. Busy is often the smokescreen for real productivity. As author Tim Kreider said, “Yes, I know we are all very busy, but what, exactly, is getting done?”</p><p>The busier we are, the less energy, attention, and time we have to do those high-impact tasks that can truly move the needle. Therefore, being busy will keep us away from the success we are looking for. In fact, there are only a few things that truly matter. We need to be aware of these priorities, protect our time and save our energy for them. We should concentrate on doing high-impact tasks as much as possible. Less contribution, busywork is just distracting. It takes away our valuable time, attention, and energy from the few really important tasks. </p><p>In a word, we should stop “acting busy” and stop celebrating it. Alternatively, we should honor those who cut out the busywork and focus their resources on the high-impact tasks that move the needle.</p><p>Productive means doing less but focusing on the most important tasks.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Nowadays, people are going to cultivate the habit of celebrating busyness. Most people are proud of being busy, just like having an honor
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="productivity" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/productivity/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Lower barrier leads to a higher success rate</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2021/03/20/lower-barrier-leads-to-a-higher-success-rate/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2021/03/20/lower-barrier-leads-to-a-higher-success-rate/</id>
    <published>2021-03-20T15:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-20T16:14:49.894Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Most people fail to develop a new habit most of the time. One of the most common mistakes is that people intend to build a strong habit and start from a difficult task. It is a bit like going to the gym for the first time and trying to lift the heaviest weights. This is not the best way to start exercising. Most people understand that we need to build our strength from our present level. This concept applies to forming any new habits.</p><p>Start from small with the initial habit. When we want to get into the habit of exercise every day, don’t expect to start from the hardest and exhaust ourselves. If we start from a high standard such as workout for two hours every day, we will feel too hard to achieve and can’t maintain consistently.<br>Exercise for two hours every day is a great obstacle, which we can’t overcome if we don’t accumulate strength.</p><p>When we start to build a new habit, the most important thing is not about the task, it’s about building the habit of getting ourselves to do the task. Once we get into the habit of letting ourselves do the task, then we can focus on increasing the intensity or increase the time of the task. Therefore, in the beginning, we should make the obstacle as low as possible, so that it’s easier and non-intimidating. </p><p>Instead of doing two-hour straight, we could start with a 15-minute routine, and then increase it slowly. Even when we feel tired or lazy, it can be done. In other words, the lower barrier, the higher success rate, and a higher success rate, the greater the achievement.</p><p>Starting from a small place and increasing the load over time goes by is the most sustainable way to build a new habit, so that we can become unstoppable.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Most people fail to develop a new habit most of the time. One of the most common mistakes is that people intend to build a strong habit a
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="productivity" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/productivity/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Peak energy time</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2021/03/14/peak-energy-time/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2021/03/14/peak-energy-time/</id>
    <published>2021-03-14T15:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T16:36:23.176Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a day, we all have a short period of natural time, during which time we will feel the most energetic and awake.</p><p>It is called peak energy time. It can be in the early morning or late at night. During the peak energy time, we tend to have better attention and concentration, clear thinking, and less distraction. </p><blockquote><p>Your internal prime time is the time of day, according to your body clock, when you are the most alert and productive. - Brian Tracy</p></blockquote><p>When we are in our peak energy time, it will be more efficient and productive. It is wise to spend time on our high-impact and complex tasks. Unfortunately, most people are not aware of their peak energy time, which leads to inefficient use of their time. Most people waste their peak energy time by working on low-impact tasks instead of high-impact tasks. It means we need to work more hours to have the same level as leverages the peak energy time. It is like fighting an unnecessary hard battle. </p><p>According to the research, most people have peak energy time in the morning. My peak energy time is between 9 AM and 12 PM which is why I enjoy doing my deep work in those hours. During the afternoon, I often lose energy, and then I use this time to do some low-impact tasks such as checking emails. For me, trying to concentrate on my work in the afternoon is usually the prescription for disaster. However, in my peak energized morning, it is very easy to concentrate. Of course, everyone has their own peak energy time. It could be at night or midnight.</p><p>Understand our peak energy time and use it to improve our productivity. Use it to complete the most complicated tasks, which require all our energy and cognitive resources. This is how we work wisely.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;In a day, we all have a short period of natural time, during which time we will feel the most energetic and awake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is called pe
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="productivity" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/productivity/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Dive into Deep Work</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2021/03/07/dive-into-deep-work/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2021/03/07/dive-into-deep-work/</id>
    <published>2021-03-07T15:45:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T16:36:19.904Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes I wonder why some people are able to achieve so many things, and how they can do them in such a short time? I found a common idea after doing some research. The most productive people do not necessarily work much more than others around them. In fact, sometimes it even takes less than 40 hours a week to work. Instead of working more time, they give priority to their works and work smarter. Instead of working more hours, they prioritize their works and working smarter. They focus on maximizing their working hours, instead of “acting busy”. This is how they can achieve better results in the same period or even in a shorter period.</p><blockquote><p>The people who achieve extraordinary results don’t achieve them by working more hours. They achieve them by getting more done in the hours they work. - Gary Keller</p></blockquote><p>Deep work is one of the ways to get the maximum effect from our working time.<br>Practicing deep work is when we work on our Most Valuable Task (MVT) in a “Flow State”. The most valuable tasks are the task that can contribute the greatest advantage, progress, and benefits much more than other tasks. When we work on the most impact task simultaneously in a Flow State ensures we fully use our brain on this one task which allows us to complete it faster. Four hours’ working time is equivalent to ten hours’ normal working time. Generally speaking, this is one of the secrets to maximize our productivity and achievement.</p><blockquote><p>To produce at your peak level you need to work for extended periods with full concentration on a single task free from distraction. Put another way, the type of work that optimizes your performance is deep work. - Cal Newport</p></blockquote><p>When we do something with Deep Work which feels like a superpower. It is a very important skill in the world that becoming more and more distracting. Therefore, as a point of action, we can start practicing Deep Work in a 90-minute time. Choose one of the Most Valuable Tasks and take 90 minutes to finish it without smartphone, social media, or things that interfere with our Flow State.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Sometimes I wonder why some people are able to achieve so many things, and how they can do them in such a short time? I found a common id
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="productivity" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/productivity/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Start from the first small task</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2021/02/28/start-from-the-first-small-task/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2021/02/28/start-from-the-first-small-task/</id>
    <published>2021-02-28T15:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T16:36:17.324Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>The secret of getting ahead is getting started. The secret of getting started is breaking your complex overwhelming tasks into small manageable tasks, and starting on the first one - Mark Twain</p></blockquote><p>This advice is simple but strong, it contains many ideas. Most of the time, when we have a big idea, we get excited about it. However, it is so difficult when we want to work on it, it is so complicated until we didn’t manage to get the start. One of the most common reasons why we tend to procrastinate is because our tasks are overwhelming, complex, or require a long-term effort.</p><p>Although, by breaking down a complex idea into some small, manageable tasks, it loses its complexity and becomes much less intimidating. After that, we can get start the simplest and most specific task, and finish it. Then, we continue to the next task, and the next one goes out. This helps us to have a clear list of things we want to do. Simply repeating this process over and over again can help us achieve the bigger ideas, projects, or goals that we are aiming for. And this is the essence of Mark Twain’s advice, small daily actions compounded over time lead to big<br>results.</p><p>Want to start working out? That’s great. But it is overwhelming and intimidating. To avoid procrastinating on the complex goal, break it down into a list of small daily tasks, to have an idea of the progress. For example, start with a short time, but keep doing it every day, and then slowly increase the time when we are used to it. Through every small and manageable daily action we accomplish, we are one step closer to achieving this big and ambitious goal.</p><p>Whenever you want to procrastinate, just remember, just take one small step and finish it. There is no harm in doing a small task, at least there is a little progress on it.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The secret of getting ahead is getting started. The secret of getting started is breaking your complex overwhelming tasks in
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="productivity" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/productivity/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How can we develop soft skills?</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2021/02/21/how-can-we-develop-soft-skills/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2021/02/21/how-can-we-develop-soft-skills/</id>
    <published>2021-02-21T15:55:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-28T15:36:57.064Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Most of the time people will ignore soft skills and focus on improving technical skills. People think soft skills are not easy to learn or we can’t improve them. However, we should treat soft skills the same way we would any technical skills.</p><p>First, where should we start? Think about our current job and the next job we are wanted to go for. What are the skills do successful people in those jobs have? Does the job involve communication with other types of people, technical and non-technical? Does having strong communication skills will benefit it?</p><p>Think about the last time we exercised the skill. Were we having any problems with communication? Are we able to convince other people about our idea? I’m pretty sure we must have some bad experiences when we talking to people or colleagues. Where we fell short and what we can do to get better next time. </p><p>We can do some research such as how to convince people about your idea, or how to make people want to listen to you. There are a ton of techniques that we can learn and practice with our coworkers or family members, even strangers. Try to push ourselves outside of our comfort zone. It does not hurt to try something new. Get comfortable with failure and keep improving and listen to feedback.</p><p>Seeking feedback makes us stronger. If someone does not like our idea, ask why and try to understand where they are coming from and what are their expectation. Sometimes an outside perspective can help us identify and understand our weaknesses. Positive and negative feedback both are important. It might be hurt at first, but we will learn faster than we do alone. </p><p>Whatever we do, make it a habit. Work on it and make a little improvement every day. </p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Most of the time people will ignore soft skills and focus on improving technical skills. People think soft skills are not easy to learn o
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="life-related" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/life-related/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Why is communication important for humans?</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2021/02/14/why-is-communication-important-for-humans/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2021/02/14/why-is-communication-important-for-humans/</id>
    <published>2021-02-14T15:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-14T17:37:04.225Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When we learned how to communicate, we start to cooperate as human beings. Communication is the process of sending and receiving messages between more than one person. Communication is the glue that holds organized people together. It is a way for us to connect with each other, exchange ideas, and learn from others.</p><p>First of all, people spread information or knowledge among people through communication. Teachers share their knowledge with their students, parents share their culture with their children, colleagues discuss their works with each other, companies exchange information with their customers, the list goes on and on. I believe that the importance of communication is like breathing, and humans can’t live without it. Without communication, the knowledge process can’t work, companies can’t operate, and humans can’t build relationships and keep together.</p><p>Communication is the basis of human relations. At first, strangers begin to talk and getting to know each other, and then more interaction will bring closer relations. Interaction helps us to express our feelings and understand each other’s emotions and thoughts. However, it will generate hatred toward other people as well, negative or positive relationships will be created.</p><p>We need someone who can communicate! I often head this sentence from the professional recruiters or business areas. In fact that it is not meaningless. The research found out that, communication and interpersonal skills remain at the top of the list of what matters most to recruiters and corporations.</p><p>There is no doubt that communication is a very important and necessary skill in human life. It does not only help to develop relationships with others but also helpful to the process of sharing knowledge and information. Every day, we have to communicate with many different people, such as families or friends, and even strangers. We should effectively improve our communication to make our life better.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;When we learned how to communicate, we start to cooperate as human beings. Communication is the process of sending and receiving messages
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="life-related" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/life-related/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Do we need soft skills in tech career?</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2021/02/06/do-we-need-soft-skills-in-tech-career/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2021/02/06/do-we-need-soft-skills-in-tech-career/</id>
    <published>2021-02-06T15:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-07T13:32:45.844Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In IT, we pretend that everyone else understands our product and know how to use it. You can have the best tools in the world, but if no one uses them, it doesn’t matter. This tends to be a problem across the board in the IT area. Even if this happens in other fields related to IT, such as security and operations. If we can’t even get all of the tech people on the same phase, it will be harder to get other people on board like marketing and business. Because of that, technical skills alone aren’t enough to be effective. We need to let other people be able to understand our idea. We need to be able to communicate to let people know what the problem is, and what solution we are providing, and why it is necessary.</p><p>The same policies apply across technology functions. If people see our product as a roadblock, if the tools require more works to them, they don’t want to use it. That’s why soft skills are important, it is the key to success in tech career, not only hard skills are required. If we can communicate with those different types of people, we will be much better at our job, no matter what type of job we are working on.</p><p>In order to get improve in soft skills. Treat soft skills the same way as we would any technical skills. Communication skills are likely to be listed as ‘soft’ but that does not mean they are easy to learn or acquire. Sometimes soft skill is easy to get started but it is hard to become expert. Although it is difficult to be an expert in this field, it is still possible for us to improve on our soft skills.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;In IT, we pretend that everyone else understands our product and know how to use it. You can have the best tools in the world, but if no 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="tech-related" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/tech-related/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How important it is to ask a question</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2021/01/30/how-important-it-is-to-ask-a-question/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2021/01/30/how-important-it-is-to-ask-a-question/</id>
    <published>2021-01-30T14:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-30T16:29:50.352Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Knowing how to ask a question is the art of conversation. Socrates’ most meaningful thought is also known as Socratic Questioning. For example, rather than the student receiving the teacher filling the mind to them, both are responsible for pushing the conversation forward. There are two ways of communication to improve the student learning from the teacher.</p><blockquote><p>I know you won’t believe me, but the highest form of human excellence is to question oneself and others - Socrates</p></blockquote><p>Socratic questioning usually having attributes as below:</p><ol><li>Concise, directed, and clear: The attention remains on the other person and should avoid complicated meaning. In order to reduce confusion, we should ask a question directly without too much retouching the sentence.</li><li>Open, yet with purpose:  Asking a meaningful question to increase the engagement of the person. There is a clear intention to make the other invited party actively participate.</li><li>Focused but tentative: The point is on the discussion, focusing on the issue, not the person. Asking questions on the point but yet does not assume the other person has the answer.</li><li>Neutral: The questioning must be pointed to the person’s perspective to get their opinion. It should not include or suggest the preferred answer. It does not guide the conversation to follow your opinion.</li></ol><p>We can manage the timing in the conversation. Allow time for the other person to respond to the questions without feeling hurried. Let the person think about your question, so we can get the true deep thought. </p><p>Regularly summarize what has been said. Let all the people understand what had been discussing and the whole idea in the conversation. Invite people to explain their idea, and bring about self-discovery through questioning. Keep the conversation focused, specific, and clearly worded.</p><p>According to science and research has confirmed that Socratic questioning provides students with positive support in enhancing critical thinking skills.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Knowing how to ask a question is the art of conversation. Socrates’ most meaningful thought is also known as Socratic Questioning. For ex
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>We should look at fact not analogy</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2021/01/24/we-should-look-at-fact-not-analogy/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2021/01/24/we-should-look-at-fact-not-analogy/</id>
    <published>2021-01-24T15:40:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-24T16:19:25.665Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We already hear people say something doesn’t work since nobody does the thing this way. We didn’t find out why we can’t do it, because of physical limitations or it is just something we can improve, but no one was doing it. We already got biased with convention or analogy to prior experiences. We are too used to think in an old way based-on previous experience since it’s always been done that way. However, we can try to think of something on a first-principles basis, that’s used in physics. We should look at the fundamentals and construct our reasoning from that, and then see if we have a conclusion that works, and it may be different from what people have done before.</p><p>Reasoning from first principles removes the assumptions and conventions. What remains is the essentials. It is a mental model we can use to improve our thinking because the essentials allow us to see where reasoning by analogy might lead to biases. The idea is to break down complicated problems into fundamental elements and then reassemble them from the ground up. This is one of the best ways to learn how to think about everything and also different perspectives that we miss.</p><p>This can happen in sports as well. A normal coach does what has already been done, and maybe he adds some tweaks, but he is just copying something that someone created before. But a good coach knows what he can and can’t do. He understands how he loses a game and how to improve on it. Everything is possible as long as it is not against the rules.</p><blockquote><p>If we never learn to take something apart, test the assumptions, and reconstruct it, we end up trapped in what other people tell us — trapped in the way things have always been done. When the environment changes, we just continue as if things were the same.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;We already hear people say something doesn’t work since nobody does the thing this way. We didn’t find out why we can’t do it, because of
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Execution is everything</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2021/01/16/execution-is-everything/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2021/01/16/execution-is-everything/</id>
    <published>2021-01-16T15:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-16T16:53:19.621Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Knowledge is not power, it is potential power. Execution will trump knowledge any day - Tony Robbins</p></blockquote><p>A lot of people saying that knowledge is power, without knowledge we can’t do anything, but owning knowledge without action also do nothing. I have been too influenced by Knowledge, I enjoy learning new things but yet less execution. The necessity of taking action appropriately is more powerful than knowing knowledge.</p><p>How many people around you know a lot of things but do nothing about it? We regularly find out the issue but do not take any action to fix it. We used to ignore the issue since it is easier than find out the solution. As is told that knowledge without action is useless. We all know that we must take action but it is easier said than done.</p><p>I’m not saying that learning knowledge is useless. Action without knowledge is aimless, it may bring in more troubles, we can’t go somewhere we are not familiar with without a navigator. Nowadays we can learn everything from internal everywhere every time. Everyone can get knowledge, it is cheap without execution. Gaining knowledge and understanding is wisdom, it is the first step before taking action, it was a tool waiting to be used. However, missing out on the action leaves our knowledge worthless. </p><p>Learning how to swim from a swimming video doesn’t make us really can swim, it needs real practice and implementation. As reading provides knowledge, it also ensures that the necessary action needs to be taken. </p><p>Knowledge is like an ax, it needs someone to use it to cut down a tree. This making the idea a simple yet powerful weapon. </p><blockquote><p>You do not get paid for having ideas. You get paid for making them happen. - Richard Branson</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is not power, it is potential power. Execution will trump knowledge any day - Tony Robbins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ikigai - a reason for being</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2021/01/11/ikigai-a-reason-for-being/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2021/01/11/ikigai-a-reason-for-being/</id>
    <published>2021-01-11T14:55:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T15:47:45.062Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In Japan, Ikigai is a concept of having a meaningful direction in life. It is a philosophy about finding a reason for being. It is about doing something you love and you are good at it, with the possibility of bringing value to other people. In most cases, Ikigai does not refer only to one’s purpose in life, without regard to others or society. It is captured by the Ikigai diagram and includes overlapping these spheres, Love, Good At, Paid For, and Needs.</p><p>This diagram helps us gain further insights into our purpose in life and seeking what we are enjoying to do.</p><p><img src="/images/ikigai.png" alt="Luck Surface Area" title="Ikigai"></p><p>What you love:<br>The things that bring us the most joy in life and make us feel fulfilled. It can a hobby, exercise, reading, or spending leisure time with people. The things do not matter whether we are good at it or we can get paid for doing it.  </p><p>What you are good at:<br>The skills you learned, talented, and be expert in. It can be sports, painting, or public speaking. However, it can also a thing that you are good at but you don’t like.</p><p>What the world needs:<br>The world here might be a small community or a global trending demand that people want. The world’s needs might include IT, engineering, medical, or innovation. This sphere involved other people and beyond people’s needs.</p><p>What you can get paid for:<br>This is related to the things that people talented at but it getting lower paid. It might be singing or passionate about art. Whether it can get higher paid depended on the demand.</p><p>There is further meaning that overlapping spheres in the diagram.</p><blockquote><blockquote><blockquote></blockquote><p>Good At + Love = Passion<br>Love + Needs = Mission<br>Needs + Paid For = Vocation<br>Paid For + Good At = Profession</p><blockquote></blockquote></blockquote></blockquote><p>The best spot within this Ikigai diagram would involve every point together. I am passionate about programming, am also skilled at it, there is a need for it in my world at the time, and I have an enjoyable job in this field with well paid. I would say I have found my Ikigai for my life.</p><p>When you love your job, it is not a job anymore.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;In Japan, Ikigai is a concept of having a meaningful direction in life. It is a philosophy about finding a reason for being. It is about 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Being wrong is not wronged</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2021/01/02/being-wrong-is-not-wronged/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2021/01/02/being-wrong-is-not-wronged/</id>
    <published>2021-01-02T15:55:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-02T18:08:10.957Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>You should take the approach that you’re wrong. Your goal is to be less wrong. - Elon Musk</p></blockquote><p>As Elon Musk said, being wrong or failed is always an option because if you are not, means you are not improving.</p><p>We all make mistakes, and we do it regularly without noticing it. No one enjoys being wrong, it is a negative emotional experience for all of us. The important thing is how do we respond when it happened to us. Some people will take responsibility and address it quickly. Some people will feel embarrassing to admit their mistake. Some people stubbornly denying being wrong and escape from the failure. People’s egos and emotions will make thing goes worth even they know it is wrong, it is hard to control the emotions.</p><p>Don’t try to shift the blame to other people. Other people might make mistakes or do wrong things with us, but we should focus only on our part. We should not argue that the mistake is caused by others. Even if they don’t admit it, but we know that we did the right thing by admitting our wrongs.</p><p>We all know admitting we are wrong is a virtue and having this habit will benefit us in our life. Struggling to admit our fault can harm our interpersonal relationship. Admitting we are wrong doesn’t mean that we are a loser. In fact, being able to own up to our mistakes takes a lot of courage and self-awareness. It is a sign of improvement. People won’t consider us a bad guy instead, they would probably respect our guts and sincerity.</p><p>After admitting and owning the mistake, we should do reflection, walking through the mistake, and learn from it provided we don’t repeat the same mistakes. The ability to fail, learn something new, and then find a solution until it works.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should take the approach that you’re wrong. Your goal is to be less wrong. - Elon Musk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Elon Musk
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hard Skills vs. Soft Skills</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/12/27/hard-skills-vs-soft-skills/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/12/27/hard-skills-vs-soft-skills/</id>
    <published>2020-12-27T15:59:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-27T17:24:24.982Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Hard skills are skills where the rules stay the same regardless of which company, circumstance, or people you work with. In contrast, soft skills are skills where the rules changes depending on the company culture and people you work with. - Lei Han</p></blockquote><p>Hard skills are measurable and most often technical skills, such as accounting and engineering. Soft skills are intangible and difficult to quantify, such as leadership and communication.</p><p>In work, hard skills help us to make confident decisions, but they do not help the foundation of communication and interaction with people around us. Business is not a machine, it is groups of people working together to achieve something.</p><p>LinkedIn CEO Jeff Weiner says “interpersonal skills are where we’re seeing the biggest imbalance. Communications is the number one skills gap”. LinkedIn’s 2018 Workforce Report found that the four most in-demand soft skills are leadership, communication, collaboration, and time management. </p><p>Soft skills can be very hard to learn since it required an internal mind change. There is some debate about the importance of soft skills and hard skills that affect work or life. However, they are both necessary and equivalent to one another.</p><p>Soft skills often provide the foundation for high emotional intelligence (EQ). EQ is the ability to identify and manage our emotions, and also the ability to understand one’s emotions. When Intelligence Quotient (IQ) is related to technical skills, EQ accounts for 90% of what makes people move up the success ladder.</p><p>Mind-body awareness is an important soft skill. It helps us from reading the room and reading others before we are consciously aware of them. Mind-body practices such as yoga and meditation help us monitor ourselves and understand our mind. This kind of self-awareness also increases empathy. Empathy is useful in work or life. Think the way of others, put ourselves in one’s shoes, help us understand more in the circumstance, and control our emotions. Such habits allow us to engage more deeply with other people.</p><p>Focus on improving soft skills such as listening and empathy with a growth mindset that will bring us an unfair advantage in work and life.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hard skills are skills where the rules stay the same regardless of which company, circumstance, or people you work with. In 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>High-income skills</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/12/19/high-income-skills/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/12/19/high-income-skills/</id>
    <published>2020-12-19T15:55:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-19T17:23:15.177Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A high-income skill is a skill that you be able to leverage to get more paid. It’s often a soft skill than a hard skill. Like communication, passion, or reliability. It delivers a unique value to your organization and allows you to control your salary because you will be in high demand.</p><blockquote><p>Your income right now is a result of your standards, it is not the industry, it is not the economy. - Tony Robbins</p></blockquote><p>You don’t always achieve your goals but you always improve your standard by doing it. To develop high-income skills, you need to increase your confidence with body language and communicate in the same ways as high earners. From the organization to the family, unclear communication can mess up everything. High-income earners consistently rate clear communication as an unfair advantage.</p><p>People who earn a high income drives every decision with their passion. When we living our life with passion, we living life instead of working a job.  We can find meaning in our work instead of just looking for the salary. A job can be a larger life strategy. High earners plan on how to leverage the existing resources they currently have to generate more income, this is the most powerful high-income skill.</p><p>Believe in the impossible is simply telling ourselves we can do it. At the end of the day, we won’t try the impossible if we don’t think there is a chance of success. In every moment, imagine that you are a high earner, what will you do in the current situation, learn a new skill to solve the problem if necessary. </p><p>As Tony Robbins said, “Who you spend time with is who you become.” Surround ourselves with the right people is the most important thing. A negative environment can’t make us think positive. Successful people know the power of networking, they surround themselves with people they wanted to become. Find people who achieved what we want, figure out how they did it, and modeling them. </p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;A high-income skill is a skill that you be able to leverage to get more paid. It’s often a soft skill than a hard skill. Like communicati
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Surround yourself with people you aspire to be</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/12/12/surround-yourself-with-people-you-aspire-to-be/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/12/12/surround-yourself-with-people-you-aspire-to-be/</id>
    <published>2020-12-12T15:55:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-12T17:29:58.149Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nowadays we are no longer demographics, we are psychographic. People living in the same area may have different interests or lifestyle. In the words of motivational speaker, Vusi Thembekwayo: “A kid living in Kuala Lumpur who has never been out of Kuala Lumpur sounds like a kid in Brooklyn New York because he watches Jay Z on Youtube. So he is completely immersed in that culture even though he never left his small little village.” No matter where we are, what we watch or read might change our identity. We will get influenced by those things we are interested in.</p><p>We often heard that “You are the average of the five people spend the most time with”. The people around you may shape who you are. When we are talking to a negative person, we will be affected by negative mindsets. When we are surrounded by people who love to talk about business, we will learn the knowledge of the business from them. People of a mind fall into the same group.</p><p>Successful people pay attention to networking. They care about who they spend time with and how people affected them. They proactively surround by people who more successful than themselves, so they can learn from them and keep improving. It is the key to have a growth mindset, which can be influenced by other people.</p><p>Surround with successful people may help you become successful. You might discover something from successful people in your subconscious mind without notice it. You might learn from their mindset, follow their way of thinking, and wanted to achieve success as them.</p><p>Hang out with people who inspire you to become better. Research for people you wanted to be an inspiration, learn from what they have done, and model them.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Nowadays we are no longer demographics, we are psychographic. People living in the same area may have different interests or lifestyle. I
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Law of Attraction</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/12/05/law-of-attraction/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/12/05/law-of-attraction/</id>
    <published>2020-12-05T15:45:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-05T17:33:50.274Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As an easy definition, the Law of Attraction is the belief that positive thoughts will bring positive experiences. It uses the power of our mind to translate whatever is in our thoughts and materialize them into reality. Simply put, all thoughts will turn into things eventually. If you think about negative things you will remain under that cloud. If you think about positive thoughts you will find a way to achieve them with action. We are acting as human magnets sending out our thoughts and emotions and attracting back more of what we have put out.</p><p>Many people think that the Law of Attraction is just visualizing what we want and wait for it to come. However, this is unreasonable. I think that is not exactly how it works. There is something missing in the idea, no matter how much time and effort we put into visualizing our success, all we will ever be is a person with a dream. As they said, we can’t have the things that we never had until we do the things that we have never done. We can’t do the same thing but expecting different results.</p><blockquote><p>Dreams don’t work unless you take action. - Roy T. Bennett</p></blockquote><p>In order to use the power of the Law of Attraction and make our dreams come true, there is one key ingredient we must integrate into our life: ACTION. Visualization and internal work are important but that doesn’t mean we can ignore the action step altogether. Once we have the inner work to get clear on mind, the action work comes far more easily. We have to take action and take all of the required steps to make our vision a reality. </p><p>As soon as we start to activate the Law of Attraction and gain more traction, it will be much easy to focus on positive things, ignore negative things, and achieve our goals.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;As an easy definition, the Law of Attraction is the belief that positive thoughts will bring positive experiences. It uses the power of o
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Distraction everywhere</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/11/30/distraction-everywhere/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/11/30/distraction-everywhere/</id>
    <published>2020-11-30T14:45:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-30T15:43:39.654Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Everything is different nowadays, distraction is everywhere and happened anytime. There are so many things that distracted our attention and took away our time. We take our smartphones with us everywhere we go, we spend a lot of time on social media, messages, and news. We got distracted more often than we’d like. The reason why we got it is one of the biggest secrets that most tech-companies don’t want us to know.</p><p>Dopamine Hacking. </p><blockquote><p>Dopamine is a neurochemical which is released every time your brain anticipates a reward such as entertainment, information, novelty, or stimulation.</p></blockquote><p>When dopamine is released, it makes us feel good, so our brain wants more of it. Just like a fat kid who loves chocolate cake. This is why our brain will stimulate us to repeat the behaviors that led to a dopamine release.</p><p>Common distractions such as social media, news, and even email have been intentionally designed to trigger an incredibly strong dopamine release. It is much more dopamine release than most of our work does. It is purposely chosen by the companies behind the apps. In fact, their entire business model depends on it. The stronger the dopamine release, the more time we will spend on these distractions, and the more money they make.</p><p>This is a concept called “attention-hacking”. It happened when we want to do something that matters most at the time like reading or study. We got distracted from our smartphone, it gave us an immediate response with dopamine release, we got addicted to it as we felt happy and enjoyable. It’s quickly destroying people’s ability to stay focused. Our brain is being hijacked by meaningless things, and it prevents us from working on meaningful things.</p><p>When we understand this concept, we will be able to easily block distractions in our daily life and allow us to focus deeply on things that truly matter.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Everything is different nowadays, distraction is everywhere and happened anytime. There are so many things that distracted our attention 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Success Leaves Clues</title>
    <link href="https://thejeffrey.me/2020/11/24/success-leaves-clues/"/>
    <id>https://thejeffrey.me/2020/11/24/success-leaves-clues/</id>
    <published>2020-11-24T15:45:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-24T17:12:59.849Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What is the key to success that they have picked up, but we can’t do it and even can’t see it. Success looks like a gift given to other people but not us. Why their success seems like effortless. </p><p>Success does not always based-on luck, it comes from hard work. If we are hungry enough, we put our effort to find a way to achieve success, with all in. We surround ourselves with the right people who managed to achieve something that we are looking for. It means surrounding the mindset of a winner and always tempting to achieve more. We can model their strategy.</p><p>Modeling means learning by following the behavior of other people. Humans naturally model each other, like children modeling their parents, follow what their parents do. Modeling is a technique used by those who willing to learn from other people. People who do modeling have a growth mindset. Those people believe that just as we learn behaviors, we can learn from the experiences of successful people. </p><p>Modeling also happens in the organization. The staff could be modeling his manager in doing some tasks, and often modeling is unintentional. Company culture is also a model that lead by the leaders in the organization, everyone modeling the culture involuntary.</p><p>Modeling in psychology has become a mainstream theory. Whether in career or life, select a person you admire to become, study the methodology behind their success, learn from their strategy, and follow the similar path to achieve it. Look for someone who already achieves the things that you wanted to do or someone who has created the kind of life that you want to live. Look into their history, what kind of difficulties they face, and how they overcome. Use their experiences to build a path to mirrors theirs.</p><blockquote><p>Success Leaves Clues - Tony Robbins</p></blockquote><p>Most successful people have the similar strategy that we can be modeling it. Modeling is a skill set that we can learn and keep improving on it.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;What is the key to success that they have picked up, but we can’t do it and even can’t see it. Success looks like a gift given to other p
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="blog" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/blog/"/>
    
      <category term="self-growth" scheme="https://thejeffrey.me/tags/self-growth/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
